He was trained to follow orders. He became a hero by defying them.
Tears of the Sun is a war, action, drama film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
Navy SEAL Lieutenant A.K.
Waters and his elite squadron of tactical specialists are forced to choose between their duty and their humanity, between following orders by
ignoring the conflict that surrounds them, or finding the courage to follow their conscience and protect a group of innocent refugees.
When the democratic government of Nigeria collapses and the country is taken over by a ruthless military dictator, Waters, a
fiercely loyal and hardened veteran is dispatched on a routine mission to retrieve a Doctors Without Borders physician.
Lieutenant A.K. Waters, played by Bruce Willis.
Dr. Lena Fiore Kendricks, played by Monica Bellucci.
James 'Red' Atkins, played by Cole Hauser.
Ellis 'Zee' Pettigrew, played by Eamonn Walker.
Kelly Lake, played by Johnny Messner.
Michael 'Slo' Slowenski, played by Nick Chinlund.
Tears of the Sun is a 2003 American war drama action
thriller film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
It depicts a fictitious U.S.
Navy SEAL team rescue mission amidst the 21st-century
version of the Nigerian Civil War.
Lieutenant A.K.
Waters (Bruce Willis) commands the team sent to rescue U.S.
citizen Dr.
Lena Fiore Kendricks (Monica Bellucci)  before the
approaching rebels reach her jungle hospital.
Willis produced Tears of the Sun through Cheyenne
Enterprises, his production company.
The film explores themes of civil war, war crimes, refugee, village, evacuation.
The tone is dark and emotional.